Here you are, sir.
Main level, please.
Right. See you on the way back.
- Bye.
- Good morning, sir.
- Morning.
- We haven't seen you for a long time.
- Nice to see you again.
- Did you have a pleasant flight?
- Very nice.
Mr. Miller of Station Security
is supposed to meet me.
- May I call him for you?
- Would you? Here he is.
- Hello, Dr. Floyd.
- Hello, Miller.
- Sorry I'm late.
- That's all right.
- You look great.
- It's nice to have you back.
- Did you have a good fIight?
- Very nice.
- Shall we go through?
- WouId you please use number 17?
Thank you, Miss Turner.
This way.
Welcome to Voiceprint Identification.
When you see the red light go on,
please state in the following order:
Your destination,
your nationality and your full name.
Surname first, Christian name
and initial.
Moon. American. Floyd, Heywood R.
Thank you. You are cleared through
Voiceprint Identification.
Thank you.
- Have i got time for breakfast?
- I think we can manage that.
How long have I got?
Your flight leaves
in an hour and 10 minutes.
I've reserved a table for you
in the Earthlight Room.
It's been seven or eight months
since you were here, hasn't it?
Let's see. Yeah, about eight months.
I suppose you saw the work
on the new section?
- Coming along great, huh?
- Yeah, it's fine.
Oh, wait.
I've got to make a couple calls.
I'll meet you in the restaurant.
- Dad?
- Hello.
- Hi, squirt. What are you doing?
Playing.
Where's Mummy?
Gone to shopping.
- Who's taking care of you?
- Rachel.
- May i speak to Rachel, please?
- She's gone to the bathroom.
Are you coming
to my party tomorrow?
i am sorry, sweetheart, but I can't.
Why not?
Well, you know, Daddy's traveling.
Very sorry about it, but i just can't. Don't i?
I'm going to send you
a very nice present, though.
All right.
- Anything special that you want?
- Yes.
What?
A telephone.
We've got Iots of telephones already.
Can't you think of anything else
for your birthday?
Something very special?
- Yes.
- What?
A bush baby.
A bush baby?
We'll have to see about that.
I want you to tell Mummy
something for me. Will you remember?
- Yeah.
- Tell Mummy that i teIephoned. Okay?
And that I'II try
to telephone again tomorrow.
Now, will you tell her that?
Yes.
Okay, sweetheart.
Have a nice birthday tomorrow.
All right.
And have a nice birthday party
tomorrow too, huh?
All right.
Okay. Now, take care
and be a good girl, won't you?
All right. Bye-bye.
Bye-bye. Happy birthday.
- Elena, how nice to see you again.
- Heywood, what a wonderful surprise.
- You're looking wonderful.
- You're looking well too.
This is my friend,
Dr. Heywood Floyd.
- I'd like you to meet Dr. Kalinan.
- How do?
- Dr. Stretyneva.
- How do you do?
And this is Dr. Andrei Smyslov.
How do you do?
I've heard a lot about you.
Do sit down.
- Well, we...
- No, no, please.
Thank you.
- Would you like a drink, doctor?
- No, thank you.
I haven't had breakfast yet.
Someone's meeting me in the restaurant.
I'll just sit with you a minute.
Then I'll be off.
- Are you quite sure?
- Quite sure, thank you.
- Well, how's Gregor?
- He's fine.
He's been doing some
underwater research in the Baltic...
...so I'm afraid we don't get to see
very much of each other these days.
- When you see him, give him my regards.
- Yes, of course.
Well, where are you all off to?
Up or down?
We're going home.
We've just spent three months
calibrating the new antenna at Tchalinko.
- What about you?
- I'm just on my way up to Clavius.
Oh, are you?
Dr. Floyd, I hope you don't think
I'm being too inquisitive...
...but perhaps you can clear up the big
mystery about what is going on there.
I'm afraid I don't know
what you mean.
It's that for the past two weeks...
...some extremely odd things
have been happening at Clavius.
- Oh, really?
- Yes, yes.
For one thing, when you phone the base,
all you get is a recording...
...which repeats that the phone lines
are temporarily out of order.
Probably having some trouble
with their equipment.